片名：仙履奇缘
仙度瑞拉
Cinderella
你就像你的名字一样甜美
You're as lovely as your name
仙度瑞拉
Cinderella
你就像夕阳一样美丽
You're a sunset in a frame
虽然穿着破旧衣旧
Though you're dressed in rags
依然掩藏不住你的高贵气质
You wear an air of queenly grace
任何人都看得出
Anyone can see
皇宫才是你的归宿
A throne would be your proper place
仙度瑞拉
Cinderella
如果你愿意倾听自己的心
If you give your heart a chance
它将会引领你
It will lead you
找到浪漫的爱情
To the kingdom of romance
你的美梦将会成真
There you'll see your dreams unfold
仙度瑞拉
Cinderella
传说中
In the sweetest story
最美的故事的女孩
Ever told
(仙履奇缘)
(很久很久以前 在一个遥远的地方…)
很久很久以前 在一个遥远的地方
Once upon a time, in a faraway land,
有个很小的王国
there was a tiny kingdom...
一个祥和、繁荣 既浪漫又传奇的国家
...peaceful, prosperous and rich in romance and tradition.
在那里有一座大庄园
Here, in a stately chateau,
住着一位丧妻的绅士 和他的小女儿仙度瑞拉
there lived a widowed gentleman and his little daughter, Cinderella.
虽然他是个慈爱的父亲
Although he was a kind and devoted father,
竭尽所能 给他的女儿最好的生活
and gave his beloved child every luxury and comfort,
他依然觉得她需要母爱
still he felt she needed a mother's care.
于是，他又再婚
And so, he married again,
他的第二任妻子出自富有家庭
choosing for his second wife a woman of good family,
也有两个 跟仙度瑞拉同样年纪的女儿
with two daughters just Cinderella's age:
她们是安泰西亚 和崔西里亚
By name, Anastasia and Drizella.
过没多久，这位绅士过世了
It was upon the untimely death of this good man, however,
而继母真正的本性 也就显露无遗
that the stepmother's true nature was revealed.
冷酷无情的继母 非常妒嫉仙度瑞拉的美貌
Cold, cruel and bitterly jealous of Cinderella's charm and beauty,
她极度自私的偏袒着
she was grimly determined to forward the interests
自己的两个笨女儿
of her own two awkward daughters.
随着光阴飞逝
Thus, as time went by,
庄园日渐残破
the chateau fell into disrepair.
因为家里的钱都浪费在 既自私又虚荣的继妹身上
For the family fortunes were squandered upon the vain and selfish stepsisters,
而仙度瑞拉却饱受虐待和羞辱
while Cinderella was abused, humiliated
最后被迫成为家中的仆人
and finally forced to become a servant in her own house.
虽然饱受欺凌
And yet, through it all,
仙度瑞拉却依然温柔善良
Cinderella remained ever gentle and kind.
每当太阳升起 她都能找到新希望
For with each dawn, she found new hope that someday
希望有一天 她梦想的幸福能实现
her dreams of happiness would come true.
你活该，谁叫你扰人清梦
Well, serves you right, spoiling people's best dreams.
我知道这是个美丽的早晨 可是…
Yes, l know it's a lovely morning, but...
我的梦也很美丽
...it was a lovely dream too.
什么样的梦？
What kind of a dream?
我不能说
an't tell.
如果说出愿望 它就不会实现了
'cause if you tell a wish, it won't come true.
而且…
And, after all...
梦就是你心中…
A dream is a wish
的愿望
Your heart makes
当你熟睡时
When you're fast asleep
在梦中你会忘却…
In dreams you will lose
你的忧伤
Your heartaches
不管你抱着
Whatever you wish for
什么样的愿望
You keep
对自己的梦
Have faith
要有信心
In your dreams and someday
有一天终将拨云见日
Your rainbow will come smiling through
无论你心里有多悲伤
No matter how your heart is grieving
只要你相信
If you keep on believing
你的梦想愿望
The dream that you wish
就会成真
Will come true
噢，那个钟声
Oh, that clock.
真是扫兴
Old killoy.
我听到了 你是在叫我起床
l hear you. ome on, get up, you say.
又是新的一天
Time to start another day.
连它都要命令我
Even he orders me around.
但有件事他们不能命令我
Well, there's one thing.
他们不能阻止我做梦
They can't order me to stop dreaming.
而且或许有一天
And perhaps someday...
我希望我的梦想
The dreams that I wish
将会成真
Will come true
无论你心里有多悲伤
No matter how your heart is grieving
只要你相信
If you keep on believing
你的梦想愿望
The dream that you wish
将会成真
Will come true
看看我找到了什么 在那边
Look what l found. Over there.
等一下
Wait a minute.
请你慢慢说
One at a time, please.
杰克，你们在吵什么？
Now, Jack, what's all the fuss about?
屋里有新老鼠 以前没见过的
New mouse in the house. Brand-new. Never saw it before.
有客人，有客人! 喔，有客人
- Visitor. Visitor! - Oh, a visitor.
那么她会需要一件衣服
Well, she'll need a dress...
不是啦 不是女的，是男的
- No, no. - lt's not a she, it's a he.
男的 喔，那就不同了
- He, he. - Oh, that does make a difference.
他会需要一件夹克和一双鞋子 必须放他出来!
- He'll need a acket and shoes... - Gotta get him out!
他在捕鼠笼里 哪里？
- lt's in a rat trap. - Where?
捕鼠笼？ 怎么不早说呢？
ln a trap? Why didn't you say so?
大家先安静
Now, now, calm down, everybody.
可怜的小东西被吓坏了
Oh, the poor little thing's scared to death.
杰克，或许 你最好先跟他解释一下
Jack, maybe you better eplain things to him.
她是仙度瑞拉
Zuk, zuk, Cinderelly.
你看，小傢伙
Now, now. Look, little guy.
你放心，没事了
Take it easy. Nothin' to worry about.
我们喜欢你 仙度瑞拉也喜欢你
We like you. Cinderelly likes you too.
她人很好，超好的
She's nice, very nice.
没有错，跟我来
That's better. Come on, now. Zuk, zuk.
这样好多了
Well, that's better.
先看看合不合身
Well, let's ust slip it on for size.
好像小了点
lt is a little snug.
但还是穿得下
But it'll have to do.
现在取个名字吧
Now, for a name.
有了，就叫奥大维
l've got one. Octavius.
简单的叫，就叫葛斯 喜欢吗，葛斯？
- But for short, we'll call you Gus. - Like it, Gus-Gus?
喜欢吗？ 葛斯，葛斯
- Like it? - Gus-Gus.
我得走了 杰克，别让他惹麻烦
l've got to hurry. See he keeps out of trouble, Jack.
也别忘了警告他小心那只猫
And don't forget to warn him about the cat.
你看过猫咪吗？
Zuk, zuk. Look, did you ever see a cat, cat?
猫咪？ 对，猫咪鲁斯佛
- Cat, cat? - Cat, cat. Lucify. That's him.
他又坏又狡猾
Meany, sneaky.
他会把你扑倒 再咬你
Jump at you. Bite at you.
他很大，就跟房子一样大
Big, big. Big as a house.
记得了吗？
Zuk, zuk, Lucify?
鲁斯佛
Lucify, zuk, zuk.
猫咪过来
Here, kitty, kitty.
快点，猫咪过来
come, kitty. Come on.
鲁斯佛!过来!
Lucifer! Come here!
我很抱歉 如果阁下你不想这么早吃早餐
l'm sorry if Your Highness obects to an early breakfast.
但这的确不是我的主意
lt's certainly not my idea to feed you first.
这是命令，来吧
lt's orders. Come on.
那是鲁斯佛吗？
Lucify. ls that Lucify?
没错，那就是他
Zuk, Lucify. That's him.
葛斯抓住鲁斯佛然后…
Gus-Gus take-a Lucify and...
让他好看 不，葛斯，不行
- ...look at! - No, Gus-Gus, no.
听我说 鲁斯佛可不好玩
Now, listen here. Lucify not funny.
他非常的坏
Lucify mean.
布鲁诺
Bruno.
布鲁诺!
Bruno!
又做梦了？
Dreaming again.
是不是在追鲁斯佛？
Chasing Lucifer?
这次逮到他了吗？
Catch him this time?
那样不好
That's bad.
楼上的人或许会听到
Suppose they heard you upstairs.
你知道规矩的
You know the orders.
如果你不想失去这个温暖的窝
So if you don't want to lose that nice, warm bed,
最好别再做那些梦
you'd better get rid of those dreams.
知道怎么做吗？
Know how?
只要学着去爱那只猫
Just learn to like cats.
我是说真的 鲁斯佛也有他的优点
No, l mean it. Lucifer has his good points too.
比如说，他…
For one thing, he...
有时候他…
Well, sometimes he...
他总会有优点的嘛
There must be something good about him.
布鲁诺
Bruno!
Oh, Bruno.
走吧，到外面去
Come on, now. Outside.
我知道这不容易
l know it isn't easy,
但至少你要试着跟他和平相处
but at least we should try to get along together.
你也一样，猫大人
And that includes you, Your Maesty.
早餐时间 大家起床了，快点
Breakfast time. Everybody up. Hurry.
快点，来吃早餐了
Come on, everybody, breakfast.
快点，来吃早餐
Come on. Let's eat breakfast.
早餐？早餐!
Breakfast? Breakfast!
是鲁斯佛，我们要怎么出去？
Lucify. How we gonna get out?
想想办法
Let's see.
我有好点子了
Listen, everybody. Got an idea.
必须要有人先溜出去
Now, somebody got to sneak out,
让鲁斯佛先去追他
get Lucify to chase him,
再把鲁斯佛引到角落
run over to the corner and keep Lucify there.
然后大家再跑出去 太好了
- Then we all run out. Zuk? - Zuk, zuk. Out.
现在我们来选一个人 向后转
Now we choose the one to do it. lbby-dibby hop.
向后转 向后转
- Hop. - Hop.
好了，向后跳 向后跳
- Ready, hop. - Hop.
跳…
Hop.
好了 跳…
- Now... - Hop, hop, hop.
跳
Hop.
你们在这里啊
Oh, there you are.
我还在找你们呢
l was wondering.
来吧，你们的早餐
All right. Breakfast is served.
这是我的
Take it easy, cluck-cluck.
放手!放手啦!
Let go! Let go, now.
住手，走开! 走开!
Stop that. Shoo! Go on. Shoo.
走开!
Shoo, shoo!
可怜的小葛斯
Poor little Gus.
这些给你
Here.
你吃吧
Help yourself.
葛斯呢？ 我想他逃掉了
Where's Gus-Gus? Well, guess he got away.
仙度瑞拉!
Cinderella!
好了，我来了
All right. l'm coming.
我的天 每天从早吼到晚
Oh, my goodness. Morning, noon and night.
仙度瑞拉!
Cinderella!
来了，来了
Coming, coming.
仙度瑞拉!
Cinderella!
我来了
l'm coming.
仙度瑞拉!
- Cinderella! - ln a minute.
再等一下
仙度瑞拉!
Cinderella!
早安，崔西里亚 睡得好吗？
Good morning, Drizella. Sleep well?
别假了
As if you care.
把衣服拿去烫 一个钟头内拿回来
Take that ironing and have it back in an hour.
一个钟头，听到没？
One hour, you hear?
好的，崔西里亚
Yes, Drizella.
早，安泰西亚 你终于来了
- Good morning, Anastasia. - Well, it's about time.
别忘了替我改衣服
Don't forget the mending.
你可别给我拖一整天
Don't be all day getting it done, either.
好的，安泰西亚
Yes, Anastasia.
进来，孩子，进来 早，母亲
- Well, come in, child, come in. - Good morning, Stepmother.
把衣服拿去洗 别忘了你该做的事
Pick up the laundry and get on with your duties.
是，母亲
Yes, Stepmother.
喔，妈…
Mother! Oh, Mother! Mother!
是你，你是故意的
You did it. You did it on purpose.
妈…!
Mother! Mother, Mother, Mother!
你又做了什么好事？
Now what did you do?
她把一只又大又丑的老鼠 放在我的茶杯里
She put it there. A big, ugly mouse, under my teacup.
鲁斯佛，告诉我 你把他怎么了？
All right, Lucifer. What did you do with him?
你别想骗人了
Oh, you're not fooling anybody.
我们来看看他在哪里
We'll ust see about this.
快点，放他走
Come on. Let him go.
还有另一只脚
Now the other one.
快点!
Come on!
噢，可怜的葛斯
Oh, poor little Gus.
鲁斯佛 你怎么就是不听话呢？
Oh, Lucifer, won't you ever learn?
仙度瑞拉!
Cinderella!
我在这里
Yes, Stepmother.
你有苦头吃了
Are you gonna get it.
把门关上，仙度瑞拉
Close the door, Cinderella.
过来这里
Come here.
你该不会是认为… 闭嘴
- You don't think that l... - Hold your tongue.
看来…
Now...
你很闲嘛
...it seems we have time on our hands.
我只是想… 安静!
- But l was only trying to... - Silence!
有时间作弄别人的话
Time for vicious practical okes.
倒不如做些更有意义的事
Perhaps we can put it to better use.
我来想想…
Now, let me see...
大厅有张大地毯
There's the large carpet in the main hall.
去把它洗干净!
Clean it!
楼上楼下的窗户
And the windows, upstairs and down.
也要擦干净!
Wash them!
对了，还有所有的挂毡和窗帘
Oh, yes. And the tapestries and the draperies.
可是我才… 再洗一次
- But l ust finished... - Do them again!
别忘了还有花园 刷洗台阶
And don't forget the garden. Scrub the terrace.
打扫大厅，还有楼上 把烟囱也清一清
Sweep the halls and the stairs. lean the chimneys.
当然，还有针线活儿 和洗衣服等等
And, of course, there's the mending and the sewing and the laundry.
对了，还有一件事
Oh, yes. And one more thing.
给鲁斯佛洗个澡
See that Lucifer gets his bath.
我的儿子 早就把他的责任给忘了
My son has been avoiding his responsibilities long enough.
该是他结婚 并且安顿下来的时候了
lt's high time he married and settled down.
那当然，陛下
Of course, Your Maesty.
但我们要有耐心 我已经夠有耐心了!
- But we must be patient. - l am patient!
你知道我也不再年轻了
But l'm not getting any younger, you know.
我想在死之前能抱到孙子
l want to see my grandchildren before l go.
我了解，陛下 不
- l understand, sire. - No.
你不了解看着自己唯一的孩子
No, you don't know what it means to see your only child
离你愈来愈远
grow farther, farther
愈来愈远的感觉
and farther away from you.
我…
l'm...
我好孤单 在这冷清的皇宫里
l'm lonely in this desolate old palace.
我想再听到小孩可爱的声音
l... l want to hear the pitter-patter of little feet again.
别伤心了，陛下
Now, now, Your Maesty.
或许我们该让他自己做主 让他自己做主？
- Perhaps if we ust let him alone... - Let him alone?
他那些不切实际的浪漫想法？
With his silly romantic ideas?
可是，陛下，爱情这种事…
But, sire, in matters of love...
爱情
Love.
只不过是男女双方 在适当的气氛下遇见彼此
Just a boy meeting a girl under the right conditions. So...
这我们可以安排 可是，陛下
- ...we're arranging the conditions. - But, Your Maesty,
要是王子怀疑的话怎么办 怀疑什么!
- if the prince should suspect. - Suspect!
王子今天要回来对吧？ 是的，陛下
- Look, the boy's coming home today. - Yes, sire.
有什么比得上开舞会 欢迎他回来更自然不过的事？
Well, what could be more natural than a ball to celebrate his return?
没有，陛下
Nothing, sire.
假如说王国里所有的未婚女孩
lf all the eligible maidens in my kingdom ust...
恰巧就在那里
...happen to be there,
他应该会看上其中的一个
why, he's bound to show interest in one of them, isn't he?
对吧？ 是的，陛下
- lsn't he? - Yes, sire.
一旦他看上某个女孩
The moment he does...
柔和的灯光
Soft lights.
浪漫的音乐
Romantic music.
加上所有的美好气氛!
All the trimmings!
这样就万无一失了
lt can't possibly fail.
对吧？
Can it?
是的，陛下!
Yes, sire. No, sire!
很好，陛下!
Very well, sire.
我这就去安排舞会在…
l shall arrange the ball for...
今晚 今晚？
- Tonight. - Tonight. Tonight?
可是，陛下… 就今晚
- Oh, but, sire... - Tonight!
还有，确定所有的未婚女孩 都要到场
And see that every eligible maid is there.
了解吗？
Understand?
是的，陛下
Yes, Your Maesty.
在树梢上
The pear-shaped toad
美丽的夜莺在歌唱
Sing, sweet nightingale
高高地…
High
在枝头上
Above me
美丽的夜莺在歌唱
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
Sing, sweet nightingale
高高地…
High
在枝头上
Above
美丽的夜莺在歌唱
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
Sing, sweet nightingale
高高在枝头上
High
美丽的夜莺在歌唱
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
美丽的夜莺
Sing, sweet
在歌唱
Nightingale
美丽的夜莺在歌唱
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
甜美的在歌唱
Sing, sweet
美丽的夜莺在歌唱
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
在歌唱
Sing
美丽的夜莺在歌唱
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
美丽的夜莺
Oh, sing, sweet
在歌唱
Oh, sing
噢，鲁斯佛!
Oh, Lucifer!
你这个坏东西!
You mean old thing.
我要好好教训你
l'm ust going to have to teach you a lesson.
奉国王陛下之名，请开门
Open in the name of the king.
这是国王的紧急通知
An urgent message from His lmperial Maesty.
谢谢 国王!
- Thank you. - From the king!
上面写什么呀，仙度瑞拉？ 上面写什么？
- What's it say, Cinderella? - What's it say? Huh?
不知道
l don't know.
他说是紧急的事
He said it's urgent.
喔…
Oh
或许我该打断她们
Maybe l should interrupt the... music lesson.
美丽的夜莺在歌唱
Sing, sweet nightingale
高高地…
High
你这笨蛋! 你是故意的
You clumsy! You did it on purpose.
是高高地在歌唱 是她的错
Be still, you!- emember, above all... - lt's her fault.
别忘了自制
...self-control.
什么事？
Yes!
我不是警告过你别打断…
l've warned you never to interrupt...
皇室刚来了通知 皇室的通知!
- This ust arrived from the palace. - From the palace!
拿过来 给我
- Give it here. - Let me have it.
我来念
l'll read it.
要召开舞会
Well, there's to be a ball.
舞会! 是为王子举办的
- A ball! - ln honor of His Highness, the prince.
王子! 皇室还命令
- Oh, the prince! - And, by royal command,
所有的未婚女孩都要参加
every eligible maiden is to attend.
那就是我们 我也未婚
- Why, that's us! - And l'm so eligible.
那表示我也能去
That means l can go too.
她想跟王子跳舞？
Her, dancing with the prince.
我的荣幸，王子陛下
l'd be honored, Your Highness.
你介意拿着我的扫帚吗？
Would you mind holding my broom?
为什么我不能去？
Well, why not?
我毕竟是这家里的一份子
After all, l'm still a member of the family.
而且这是皇室的命令 所有的未婚女孩都得参加
And it says, ''By royal command, every eligible maiden is to attend.''
是这样没错
Yes, so it does.
没什么理由不准你去
Well, l see no reason why you can't go.
如果你能完成工作的话 我会的，我保证做完
- lf you get all your work done. - Oh, l will. l promise.
还有，如果 你找得到合适的衣服的话
And if you can find something suitable to wear.
我会找到的 谢谢你，继母
l'm sure l can. Oh, thank you, Stepmother.
妈，你知道 你刚才说了什么吗？
Mother, do you realize what you ust said?
当然
Of course.
我是说“如果”
l said ''if.''
哦“如果”
Oh. ''lf.''
很漂亮吧？
lsn't it lovely?
是我妈的 它很漂亮，可是旧了
- lt was my mother's. - lt's pretty, but it looks old.
或许式样有些老旧 不过我可以改一改
Well, maybe it is old-fashioned, but l'll fi that.
你要怎么做？ 等一等
- How do you do it? - Wait a minute.
书里应该有些好点子
There ought to be some good ideas in here.
Uh-huh.
这一款 很好看
- This one. - Oh, very nice. Nice.
我喜欢 真的很美
- Like it. - lt'll be easy.
我可以把袖子改短 做一点裙花
l'll have to shorten the sleeves, l'll need a sash,
领子再做一点装饰 仙度瑞拉!
- a ruffle, something for a collar... - inderella!
又怎么啦？ 仙度瑞拉!
- Oh, now what do they want? - Cinderella!
好吧
Oh, well.
看来，我的衣服 只好再等一会儿了
l guess my dress will ust have to wait.
仙度瑞拉!
- Cinderella! - Cinderella!
好啦，这就来了
All right, all right. l'm coming.
可怜的仙度瑞拉
Poor Cinderelly.
才刚闲下来 就又被叫去干活
Every time she finds a minute, that's the time when they begin it.
仙度瑞拉!叫个不停 仙度瑞拉!
- inderelly, Cinderelly. - Cinderella!
仙度瑞拉… 从早到晚被叫个不停
Cinderelly, Cinderelly Night and day it's Cinderelly
砍柴生火，打点早餐
Make the fire Fix the breakfast
清洗碗盘，擦擦桌子
Wash the dishes Do the moppin'
扫扫地板，清清灰尘
And the sweepin' and the dustin'
成天到晚被差遣着
They always keep her hoppin'
总是忙得转呀转
She go around in circles
就算疲惫不堪
Till she very, very dizzy
还是不让她歇息 一刻都不得闲的仙度瑞拉
- Still they holler - Keep a-busy, Cinderelly
没错，就是没办法休息
Yeah. Keep a-busy.
你们知道吗？
You know what?
仙度瑞拉无法参加舞会 什么？
- Cinderelly not go to the ball. - What?
不能去？ 你说什么？
- Not go? - What did you say?
你们看好了
You'll see.
她们会要她…
They'll fi her.
不停的工作
Work, work, work.
她永远没时间做她的衣服
She'll never get her dress done.
可怜的仙度瑞拉
Poor Cinderelly.
嘿!我们可以做啊!
Hey! We can do it!
只要我们同心协力
We can do it We can do it
就能帮仙度瑞拉 做出美丽的衣旧
We can help our Cinderelly We can make the dress so pretty
这真的不难
There's nothing to it, really
我们可以做出裙花 在上面别上蝴蝶结
We'll tie a sash around it Put a ribbon through it
仙度瑞拉穿上我们做的衣旧
When dancing at the ball she'll be more beautiful than all
就会成为舞会上最美丽的女孩
In the lovely dress we'll make for Cinderelly
快点，快点…
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry
我们必须帮助仙度瑞拉
Gonna help our Cinderelly
没时间浪费了
Got no time to dilly-dally
我们得快动手 我用剪刀把它剪开
- We got to get it goin' - l'll cut it with the scissors.
我来做针线活 针线活是女人的事
- And l can do the sewing. - Leave the sewing to the women.
你去找些缎带
You go get some trimmin'.
我们来帮仙度瑞拉 做漂亮的衣旧
And we'll make a lovely dress for Cinderelly
We'll make a lovely dress for Cinderelly
跟我来，葛斯 我知道上哪儿找
Follow me, Gus-Gus. l know where to go.
这衣服一定会很漂亮
Find the pretty-pretty for this dress.
仙度瑞拉一定会感到惊喜
Cinderelly will be surprised.
惊喜，惊喜
Surprise, surprise. Very surprised.
还有这个，我的拖鞋 别忘了…
And this, too, my slippers. Don't forget...
这件衣服也要 把纽扣修补一下
- Take my dress. - Here, mend the buttonholes.
把裙子烫一烫，小心裙摆 仙度瑞拉？
- Press my skirt, and mind the ruffle. - And inderella?
是？ 等你做好了
- Yes? - When you're through,
在你开始日常的活儿之前
and before you begin your regular chores,
我还有一些小事 知道了
- l have a few little things. - Very well.
为什么 其他人都能穿漂亮的衣服
l don't see why everybody else has nice things to wear,
而我老是穿这些旧衣服
and l always end up in these old rags.
这个腰带丑死了
This sash! l wouldn't be seen dead in it.
还说，这条项链才丑呢
You should talk. These beads! l am sick of looking at them.
垃圾 真是讨厌
- Trash. - Oh, l hate this.
来吧，小心点
ome on, and be care-fee.
对，要非常小心
Yes, yes. eal care-fee.
我们可以用这个，葛斯
We can use that, Gus-Gus.
漂亮，漂亮
Pretty, pretty.
小心，鲁斯佛在
Look out. Lucify!
哦，项链!
Oh! Beads!
好漂亮的项链!
Very pretty beads!
梦就是你心中的愿望
A dream is a wish your heart makes
当你熟睡时
When you're fast asleep
在梦中你会忘却你的忧伤
In dreams you will lose your heartaches
不管你抱着什么样的愿望
Whatever you wish for, you keep
Have faith in your dreams and someday
无论你心里有多悲伤
No matter how your heart is grieving
只要你相信
If you keep on believing
你的愿望就会实现
The dream that you wish will come true
好了，一，二，三，四 五，六，七，八
Okay. One, two, three, four, five, si, seven, eight.
不管你抱着什么样的愿望
Whatever you wish for, you keep
好了
All right.
加油，加油
Heave-ho.
加油
Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
你的梦想愿望将会成真
The dream that you wish will come true
将会成真
Will come true
什么事？ 马车来了
- Yes? - The carriage is here.
仙度瑞拉
Why, Cinderella,
你怎么还没准备好？ 我不去了
- you're not ready, child. - l'm not going.
不去了？ 那有多可惜啊
Not going? Oh, what a shame.
不过，当然，以后还有机会的
But of course, there will be other times.
是啊，晚安
Yes. Good night.
算了吧
Oh, well.
皇室舞会也没什么？
What's a royal ball?
我想那一定很无聊
After all, l suppose it would be frightfully dull
枯燥无味，一定很…
and boring and completely...
一定很棒
ompletely wonderful.
那是我的… 惊喜!
- lt's my... - Surprise!
惊喜! 惊喜!
- Surprise! - Surprise!
生日快乐 不是啦
- Happy birthday! - No, no, no, no!
我做梦也想不到
Well, l never dreamed it.
好棒的惊喜
lt's such a surprise.
我怎么能…
Oh, how can l ever...?
喔，太谢谢你们了
Oh, thank you so much.
记得，当你们见到王子时
emember, when you're presented to His Highness,
一定要… 等等!
- be sure... - Wait!
请等一下!
Please, wait for me.
很漂亮吧？ 你们喜欢吗？
lsn't it lovely? Do you like it?
这件衣服可以吗？
Do you think it will do?
仙度瑞拉! 妈，不可以
- Cinderella! - Mother, she can't.
不可以 她不能去!
- Oh, no. - You can't!
安静
Girls, please.
无论如何我们说好了的
After all, we did make a bargain.
是不是，仙度瑞拉？
Didn't we, Cinderella?
而我从不食言
And l never go back on my word.
真聪明啊
How very clever.
这项链
These beads,
摸起来还真舒服呢
they give it ust the right touch.
你说是不是，崔西里亚？
Don't you think so, Drizella?
我才不觉得呢，她…
No, l don't. l think she's...
噢!你这个小偷!
Oh! Why, you little thief!
那是我的项链，还给我 不
- They're my beads. Give them here. - Oh, no.
她还偷我的腰带
And look, that's my sash. Wearing my sash.
是我的! 不要
- She can't! - Oh, please.
求求你不要
Please, no.
小偷!
Thief! You ungrateful little...
孩子们
Girls, girls.
夠了 你们两个快点走了
That's quite enough. Hurry along now, both of you.
我不要你们坏了情绪
l won't have you upsetting yourselves.
晚安
Good night.
你会忘却你的忧伤
You will lose your heartache
不管你抱着什么样的愿望
Whatever you wish for, you'll keep
噢，不 这不是真的
Oh, no. No, it isn't true.
对自己的梦要有信心
Have faith in your dreams and someday
没有用的
lt's ust no use.
有一天一切终将拨云见日
Your rainbow will come smiling through
一点都没有用
No use at all.
无论你心里有多悲伤
No matter how your heart is grieving
只要相信
If you keep on believing
我不再相信了 你的梦想愿望
- l can't believe. Not anymore. - The dream that you wish
没什么好相信的了 就会成真
- Will come true - There's nothing left to believe in.
没什么 真的吗，亲爱的？
- Nothing. - Nothing, my dear?
你不会是说真的吧 我是说真的
- Oh, now you don't really mean that. - Oh, but l do.
胡说，孩子!
Nonsense, child!
如果你不相信的话 我就不会在这里了
lf you'd lost all your faith, l couldn't be here.
我不是来了吗？
And here l am.
来，擦干眼泪
Oh, come now. Dry those tears.
你不能像这样去参加舞会
You can't go to the ball looking like that.
舞会？可是我不能… 你当然能去
- The ball? Oh, but l'm not... - Of course, you are.
但我们得赶快
But we'll have to hurry,
因为就算是奇迹 也是需要时间的
because even miracles take a little time.
奇迹？ 你看
- Miracles? - Watch.
我的魔术棒到哪去了？ 我记得…
What in the world did l do with that magic wand? l was sure...
魔术棒？ 真是奇怪
- Magic wand? - That's strange.
那你一定是… 我都放…
- l always... - Then you must be...
神仙教母 当然了
Your fairy godmother? Of course.
我的魔术棒到底在…
Where is that wand? l...
喔，我忘了
Oh! l forgot.
我收起来了
l put it away.
你们看她？ 她怎么变的？
- Look at what she did. - How'd she do it?
让我想想
Now, let's see.
首先你需要的是…
l'd say the first thing you need is...
一个南瓜 一个南瓜？
- ...a pumpkin. - A pumpkin?
接下来要念咒语
Now... the magic words.
莎拉卡都拉，梅气卡布拉 比比迪巴比迪布
Sala-gadoola-menchika-boo-la Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
念完之后 会变成什么呢？
Put 'em together and what have you got?
比比迪巴比迪布
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
莎拉卡都拉，梅气卡布拉 比比迪巴比迪布
Sala-gadoola-menchika-boo-la Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
它会变魔术 无论你信不信
It'll do magic believe it or not
比比迪巴比迪布
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
莎拉卡都拉就是梅气卡布拉
Now sala-gadoola means a menchika-boolaroo
但关键的咒语是
But the thing-a-ma-bob that does the job
比比迪巴比迪布
Is bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
莎拉卡都拉，梅气卡布拉 比比迪巴比迪布
Sala-gadoola-menchika-boo-la Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
念完之后 会变成什么呢？
Put 'em together and what have you got
比比迪巴比迪布…
Bibbidi-bobbidi, bibbidi-bobbidi Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
你们看 真是太棒了
- Oh, looky. - lsn't it wonder-fee?
喔，好美的马车
Oh, it's beautiful.
是啊
Yes, isn't it?
当然了，有这么高贵的马车
With an elegant coach like that, of course,
就得配上…
we'll simply have to have...
…老鼠 老鼠？
- ...mice! - Mice?
喔，太好了
Oh, this really is nice.
我们会有4匹马的马车
Why, we'll have a coach and four when we're through.
只要挥一挥魔术棒就能完成
Just a wave of my stick, and to finish the trick,
比比迪巴比迪布
bibbidi, bobbidi, boo.
怎么搞的？
Gracious, what did l do?
我确定有4只 怎么少了1只
l was sure there were four. There should be one more.
你在这儿啊
There you are.
比比迪巴比迪布
Bibbidi, bobbidi, boo.
可怜的鲁斯佛
Oh, poor Lucifer.
他也该尝点苦头了
Serves him right, l'd say. Now...
好了，然后呢… 喔，对了
Where were we? Oh, goodness, yes.
你不能去舞会，如果没有…
You can't go to the ball without...
马儿 还要另一匹？
- ...a horse. - Another one?
今晚，就换点新鲜的 你来当马夫
But tonight, for a change, you will handle the reins,
就坐在驾驶座上
and sit in the driver's seat too.
你就改当马夫好了
For instead of a horse, you're the coachman, of course.
比比迪巴比迪布
Bibbidi, bobbidi, boo.
这样应该完成了 除了…对了
That does it, l guess, ecept for... oh, yes!
最后一项 那就是你了
The finishing touch. And that's you.
没错，布鲁诺 今晚你要当侍童
Yes, Bruno, that's right, you'll be footman tonight.
比比迪巴比迪布
Bibbidi, bobbidi, boo.
好了，赶快进去吧，亲爱的 不能再浪费时间了
Well, well, hop in, my dear. We can't waste time.
可是… 你不用谢我了
- But... - Now don't try to thank me.
我只是… 我是很谢谢你，可是…
Oh, l wasn't... l mean, l do, but...
可是你不觉得我穿得…
But don't you think my dress...
是啊，你穿得很美，亲爱…
Yes, it's lovely, dear. Lov...
我的天，孩子! 你不能穿这样去!
Good heavens, child. You can't go in that!
让我来看看
Now, let's see, dear.
配合你的身材和眼睛的颜色
Your size and the shade of your eyes.
需要简单和可爱一点的衣服
Something simple, but daring too.
交给我就可以了 这件礼服一定很美丽
Oh, ust leave it to me. What a gown this will be.
比比迪巴比迪布…
Bibbidi-bobbidi. Bibbidi-bobbidi.
比比迪巴比迪布
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo.
喔，好漂亮的衣服
Oh, it's a beautiful dress.
你们有见过 这么美丽的衣服吗？
Did you ever see such a beautiful dress?
还有，你们看玻璃鞋
And look, glass slippers.
这就像美梦一般
Why, it's like a dream.
一个好美的梦实现了
A wonderful dream come true.
是啊，孩子
Yes, my child.
但是，就像所有梦境一样
But like all dreams,
我怕它只能维持短暂的时间
well, l'm afraid this can't last forever.
这一切只能发生在午夜之前 然后…
You'll have till midnight, then...
午夜？那没关系
Midnight? Thank you.
不不不，你得听我说 亲爱的
Now, now, now, ust a minute. You must understand, my dear.
当12点钟声响起时 咒语就会被解除
On the stroke of 1 2 the spell will be broken,
所有的一切都会变回来
and everything will be as it was before.
我了解，可是…
Oh, l understand, but...
这已经比我希望的好太多了
...it's more than l ever hoped for.
祝福你了，孩子
Bless you, my child.
惨了!
l... Goodness me!
已经很晚了，快点去 舞会可是不等人的
lt's getting late. Hurry up, dear. The ball can't wait.
好好的玩 尽情跳舞开心点
Have a good time. Dance. Be gay.
现在快去吧，上路了
Now, off you go. You're on your way.
神奇的比比迪巴比迪布…
With a bibbidi-bobbidi Bibbidi-bobbidi
比比迪巴比迪布
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
玻多利卡优金芳登公主陛下
Princess Frederica Janie de la Fontain.
法俄塞尔奥古斯坦小姐
Mademoiselle Augustina DuBois.
奥古斯坦将军之女
Daughter of General Pierre DuBois.
这孩子真不给面子
The boy isn't cooperating.
南若拉科隆爵士之女
Mademoiselle Leonora Mercedes de la Tour.
维多利亚小姐
Daughter of olonel and Madame de la Tour.
我真是不明白
l can't understand it.
这当中总有一个 能当个好妈妈
There must be at least one who'd make a suitable mother.
陛下 能当个好妻子
- Sire. - A suitable wife.
安泰西亚
Mademoiselles Drizella
以及崔西里亚科曼妮小姐
and Anastasia Tremaine.
科曼妮夫人之女
Daughters of Lady Tremaine.
我放弃了 连我都看不上，何况是王子
l give up. Even l couldn't epect the boy to...
请容我这么说，陛下 我早就提醒过您了
Well, if l may say so, Your Maesty, l did try to warn you,
但是您想得太浪漫了
but you, sire, are incurably romantic.
你是想在今天的舞会里
No doubt you saw the whole pretty picture in detail.
看到王子回礼时
The young prince... bowing to the assembly.
突然愣住，他往前一看
Suddenly he stops. He looks up.
就在他眼前
For, lo, there she stands.
他梦中的女孩
The girl of his dreams.
不管她是谁，她来自何方 那都不重要
Who she is or whence she came, he knows not, nor does he care,
因为他的心告诉自己
for his heart tells him that here,
那就是他的真命天女
here is the maid predestined to be his bride.
真是好美的童话故事呀 陛下
A pretty plot for fairy tales, sire.
但在现实生活中
But in real life, oh, no.
那是注定不会发生的
No! lt was foredoomed to failure.
不会发生？
Failure, eh?
你自己亲眼看看 你这个自大狂
Take a look at that, you pompous windbag!
她是谁？你见过她吗？
Who is she? You know her?
没有，陛下 我没见过她
No, sire. l've never seen her before.
她真是美
That's one thing in her favor.
华尔滋，快，华尔兹
The wallz. uick, the wallz!
灯光
Lights.
The lights.
你还说不会成功？
Failure, eh?
好了
Well...
现在可以好好睡个觉了
Now for a good night's sleep.
是啊，陛下 我想我也该睡了
Oh, quite so, sire. l believe l, too...
你给我好好待这儿
You will stay right here.
确定没人打扰他们
See they're not disturbed,
王子求婚的时候 再马上通知我
and when the boy proposes, notify me immediately.
“马上通知我” 还有记住…
- ''Notify me immediately.'' - And remember:
如果出了什么事…
lf anything goes wrong...
妈，她是谁啊？ 你认识她吗？
- Who is she, Mother? - Do we know her?
王子的样子好像认识她
Well, the prince certainly seems to.
我想我没见过她 我也是
- l know l've never seen her. - Nor l.
但她真的是… 等等
But she certainly is... Wait.
她看起来有点眼熟
There is something familiar about her.
这就是爱
So this is love
爱让生活
So this is what makes life
充满欢乐
Divine
我的心充满喜悦
I'm all aglow
现在我明白了 现在我明白了
- And now I know - And now I know
天堂的钥匙
The key to all heaven
就在我的手中
Is mine
我的心有着翅膀
My heart has wings
可以飞翔
And I can fly
飞到天空中
I'll touch every star
在繁星星里
In the sky
原来这就是奇迹
So this is the miracle
我一直梦想的奇迹
That I've been dreaming of
原来
So this
这就是
Is
爱
Love
喔，糟了
Oh, my goodness.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
午夜到了 是啊，那没关…
- lt's midnight. - Yes, so it is. But why...?
再见 不，等等
- Goodbye. - No, wait.
你不能现在离开，我们才… 我必须走了
- You can't go now. lt's only... - Oh, l must. Please.
求求你 为什么？
- Please, l must. - But why?
我… 王子
Well, l... Oh, the prince.
我还没见到王子 王子？
- l haven't met the prince. - The prince?
你难道不知道…
But didn't you know...?
再见 不，等一下
- Goodbye. - No, wait.
回来，请你回来
ome back. Please come back.
我什至还不知道你的名字 我要怎么找你？
l don't even know your name. How will l find you?
等等!请等一下!
Wait! Please wait.
再见
Goodbye.
小姐
Oh, l say. Young lady!
等一下! 王子!
- Wait! - The prince!
小姐，你别走啊
Mademoiselle. Senorita.
等一下
Just a moment.
快来!快点!
Guard! Guard!
拦下马车! 关上大门!
Stop that coach! lose those gates!
去追那马车!
Follow that coach!
别让他们逃了!
Open those gates!
对不起
l'm sorry.
我一玩什么都忘了
l guess l forgot about everything.
什至忘了时间，可是…
Even the time, but...
可是这一切真的好美
But it was so wonderful.
他好英俊，当我们跳舞时…
And he was so handsome, and when we danced...
我想就算是王子也不比他…
Oh, l'm sure even the prince himself couldn't have been more...
不比他…
...more...
算了，这都结束了 仙度瑞拉
- Oh, well, it's over, and... - Cinderelly.
你看!鞋子!
Look, look! The slipper!
是啊，你的鞋子 你看你的鞋子
- Yeah, your slipper. - Your slipper, inderelly.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢你给我的一切
Thank you so much, for everything.
陛下，我就直截了当的说吧
Your Majesty, l see no point in beating about the bush.
我很遗憾禀报你，陛下
l regret to inform you, sire,
那位小姐不见了
that the young lady has disappeared,
她只留下了这只玻璃鞋
leaving behind only this glass slipper.
就这样，我马上去
Yes. l'll do it.
不，我不敢
No. l just can't.
好吧，进来
Well, come in.
进来!
ome in!
陛下… 所以他求婚了？
- Your Maesty... - So, he's proposed already?
快告诉我 这…
- Tell me about it. - Well...
她是谁？ 我没机会…
- Who is she? - l didn't get a chance...
没关系 我们还有更重要的事要讨论
No matter. We've more important things to discuss.
婚礼的安排
Arrangements for the wedding,
寄邀请函，订那天为国定假日
invitations, a national holiday.
诸如此类的事 可是，陛下…
- All that sort of thing. - But, sire...
来，来抽根雪茄 多来几根
Here. Have a cigar. Take a few more.
可是…
But...
你最好先学会怎么分雪茄
Better practice passing these out.
请您…
But if you'd...
您听我说 至于你呢，我的朋友
- ...only listen. - And for you, my friend.
陛下，陛下… 一位爵士
- Your Maesty, please... - A knighthood.
在此，我封你为…
l hereby dub you Sir...
对了，你想要什么名称？ 陛下？
- By the way, what title would you like? - Sire?
她逃走了 “她逃走了”？
- She got away. - Sir ''She Got Away''?
这是很特别的名称 但如果你要的话…
A peculiar title, but if that's what you...
什么？她怎么了？
She what? Why, you...
你…你这叛徒!
You... you traitor!
不，陛下，别忘了你的血压
Now, sire. emember, your blood pressure.
叛徒!
Treason!
不，陛下，不要!
No, sire. No!
没用的傢伙!
Sabotage!
你不是跟王子在一起吗？
You were in league with the prince.
我有阻止她
l tried to stop her,
可是她就消失了 你真会鬼扯
- but she vanished into thin air. - A likely story.
是真的，陛下 我们只找到她的玻璃鞋
But it's true, sire. All we could find was this glass slipper.
这件事从头到尾都是阴谋!
The whole thing was a plot!
可是陛下，王子爱她!
But, sire, he loves her.
不找到那女孩 他是不会罢休的
He won't rest till he finds her.
他决心要娶她
He's determined to marry her.
什么？你说什么？
What? What did you say?
陛下，王子发誓什么人都不娶
The prince, sire, swears he'll marry none
一定要找到能穿这只鞋的女孩
but the girl who fits this slipper.
他是这么说？
He said that, did he?
那就搞定了!
We've got him!
可是陛下 可能有很多女孩穿得下这只鞋
But, sire, this slipper may fit any number of girls.
那是他的问题 他既然说了
That's his problem. He's given his word.
就不能反悔 是啊，陛下
- We'll hold him to it. - No, Your Highness.
这可不关我的事
l'll have nothing to do with it.
你让全国的女孩都试试这只鞋
You'll try this on every maid in my kingdom.
谁穿得上这只鞋
And if the shoe fits...
就把她带进宫
...bring her in.
遵命，陛下
Yes, Your Maesty.
仙度瑞拉？仙度瑞拉？
Cinderella? Cinderella?
仙度瑞拉又跑哪儿去了？ 是？
- Cinderella! Where is that...? - Yes?
我在这儿 我的女儿在哪里？
- Here l am. - My daughters, where are they?
我想她们还在睡
l think they're still in bed.
别光只是站着!
Don't ust stand there!
马上把早餐端上来 快一点!
Bring up the breakfast trays at once. And hurry!
哇，我在想出了什么事
Wow. l wonder what's the matter.
她是怎么了？ 我不知道
- What's the matter with her? - l don't know.
我们去查一查，来吧
Let's find out. ome on.
崔西里亚!
Drizella!
怎么啦？ 快点起床，马上
- What? - Get up. uick. This instant.
一刻也不能迟
We haven't a moment to lose.
安泰西亚
Anastasia.
起来，安泰西亚
Get up, Anastasia.
什么事？
What for? Why?
全国的人都在讨论这事
Everyone's talking about it, the whole kingdom.
快点，他随时都会到 谁？
- Hurry now. He'll be here any minute. - Who will?
爵士大人 他已经找了一整晚了
The grand duke. He's been hunting all night.
找什么？ 那个女孩
- Hunting? - For that girl.
昨晚在舞会上 留下一只鞋的女孩
The one who lost her slipper at the ball last night.
他们说他疯狂的爱上她
They say he's madly in love with her.
你是说爵士大人？ 不，我是说王子!
- The duke is? - No, no. The prince!
王子!
The prince!
你这笨手笨脚的傢伙
You clumsy little fool.
快清一清 然后帮我的女儿们打扮
lean that up. And then help my daughters dress.
有什么用？ 他不是爱上那女孩吗？
- What for? - lf he's in love with that girl,
我们费什么劲呢？
why should we even bother?
你们两个好好听着
Now you two, listen to me.
你们还是有机会的
There is still a chance that one of you can get him.
有机会？ 怎么说呢，妈？
One of us? Why, Mother, what do you mean?
因为…
Just this:
没有人，什至是王子本人 都不知道这女孩是谁
No one, not even the prince, knows who that girl is.
我们知道，是仙度瑞拉!
We know! We know! Cinderelly!
唯一的线索是一只玻璃鞋
The glass slipper is their only clue.
现在，爵士奉命…
Now, the duke has been ordered to try it
要全国的女孩试穿它
on every girl in the kingdom.
只要能找到 适合这只鞋的女孩
And if one can be found whom the slipper fits,
奉国王之命
then, by the king's command,
那个女孩就是王子的新娘
that girl shall be the prince's bride.
王子的新娘 王子的新娘!
- His bride. - His bride!
仙度瑞拉，快拿我的东西来
Cinderella, get my things together.
别管她，先拿我的
Never mind her. Get mine right away.
她是怎么搞的？
What's the matter with her?
醒一醒，傻子 我们得换衣服了
- Wake up, stupid. - We've gotta get dressed.
衣服，是啊
Dressed. Oh, yes.
喔，得换件衣服
We must get dressed.
穿这样不能见人
lt would never do for the duke to see me...
妈，你看她？
Mother, did you see what she did?
你怎么可以让她… 安静!
- Are you ust going to let her...? - uiet!
这就是爱
So this is love
她想做什么？ 不知道，我们得监视她
- What's she gonna do? - l don't know. Gotta watch her.
快点
ome on.
仙度瑞拉! 仙度瑞拉!
- Cinderelly! - Cinderelly!
原来这就是奇迹 小心!你的背后!
- So this is the miracle - Look out! Behind you!
我一直梦想的奇迹
That I've been dreaming of
什么？
What?
喔，不!
Oh, no!
求求你别这样!
No, please!
喔，你不能这样，你不能
Oh, you can't, you ust can't.
放我出去!放我出去!
Let me out! You must let me out!
你不能把我关在这里!
You can't keep me in here!
求求你!
Oh, please.
不行，她不能这样 她不能把仙度瑞拉关着
No, no. She can't do it. She can't lock up inderelly.
我要…
l'm gonna...
我求求你
Please, please.
我们要拿到钥匙，葛斯 我们一定要拿到钥匙
We gotta get that key, Gus-Gus. We ust gotta get that key.
停车
Whoa.
他来了，那个爵士
He's over here, the duke-duke.
谁？ 带着玻璃鞋的爵士大人
- The who? - The grand duke with the slipper.
我们得赶快拿到钥匙 对，钥匙，快点
- Gotta get that key, quick. - Yup, yup. Key, key. uick, quick.
喔，妈妈 他来了…
Oh, Mother, Mother, he's here, he's here.
爵士大人 我看起来可以吗？
- The grand duke - Do l look all right?
我好兴奋喔 女孩们
- l ust don't know what l'll do. - Girls.
记住，这是你们最后的机会 别让我失望
Now, remember, this is your last chance. Don't fail me.
爵士大人驾到
Announcing His lmperial Grace, the grand duke.
欢迎莅临寒舍，大人
You honor our humble home, milord.
很好 她们是我的女儿
- uite so. - May l present my daughters,
崔西里亚和安泰西亚
Drizella, Anastasia.
大人
Your Grace.
很好，很好
Yes. harmed, l'm sure.
请大人宣读皇室命令
His Grace will read the royal proclamation.
本人在此宣读…
''All loyal subects of His lmperial Maesty
国王陛下的命令 此事有关…
are hereby notified by royal proclamation in regard to a certain
玻璃鞋的事
glass... slipper.
国王命令能穿上这只…
lt is decreed...''
我的玻璃鞋!
Why, that's my slipper!
真好笑，那是我的鞋!
Well, l like that. lt's my slipper!
不是，是仙度瑞拉的鞋!
No, no! lt's Cinderelly's slipper!
她怎么能夠… 女孩们
- How can she stand there...? - Girls, girls.
别忘了礼貌
Your manners.
真是万分抱歉，大人
A thousand pardons, Your Grace.
请您继续念吧 好吧
- Please continue. - Yes, quite so.
刚才念到… 即日起…
Oh, yes. ''lt is upon this day decreed
命令到全国各地寻访
that a quest be instituted throughout the length of our domain,
寻访的目的和规定如下：
the sole and epress purpose of such quest to be as follows:
王国境内所有的女孩
That every maid throughout the kingdom without eception,
都得试穿这只玻璃鞋
shall try on her foot this slipper of glass,
不管是哪个女孩 只要能穿上这只鞋的女孩
and should one be found upon whose foot this slipper shall properly fit...
就是此次要找寻的女孩
...such maiden shall be acclaimed the obect of this search
她将会被视为国王…
and shall be looked upon as the true love of His oyal Highness,
的爱子和继承人 也就是王子的真爱
our beloved son and heir, the noble prince.
王子将会屈膝
Said prince will, upon bended knee,
要求，诚挚的恳求
beg, request, or if need be, implore
这位女孩嫁给他
said maiden that he be granted her hand in marriage.
如果这个女孩…
答应求婚的话 这对新人必须立誓珍爱彼此
Whereupon, should the maiden look with favor upon his suit,
shall the couple pledge their troth...
日后，国王驾崩之后
...and upon the inevitable demise of His Maesty the king,
这对新人将继承王位 成为这个王国的国王和皇后
succeed to the throne to rule over the land as king and queen of our kingdom.
谨此
So be it.''
你一定累坏了，大人
You must be quite fatigued, Your Grace.
请喝杯茶吧？
May we offer you some tea?
什么？茶？
What? Tea?
谢谢夫人，不用了
Thank you, madam, no.
我们必须进行试穿这只鞋了
We must proceed with the fitting.
那当然 安泰西亚
Of course. Anastasia dear.
你看 我就知道是我的鞋嘛
There. l knew it was my slipper.
完全合脚
Eactly my size.
我总是穿一样的尺寸
l always wear the same size.
我一看到它，就说…
As soon as l saw it, l said...
喔，是这样的…
Oh, well...
我的脚今天可能大了点
lt may be a trifle snug today.
你也知道跳了一整晚的舞
You know how it is, dancing all night.
我真是不明白
l can't understand why.
以前总是合穿的呀
lt's always fit perfectly before.
你根本就不会穿
l don't think you're half trying.
妈，你可不可以…
Mother, can you...?
安静，亲爱的 别把大人吵醒了
uiet, my dear. We mustn't disturb His Grace.
年轻人，你确定 你穿的是左脚？
Young man, are you sure you're trying it on the right foot?
是左脚没错，可是…
Oh, it's the right foot, but...
玻璃鞋就是靠不住 来吧，葛斯，快点
- These glass shoes aren't reliable. - ome on. Hurry.
上楼去…
Up the stairs. Up the stairs!
要小心鲁斯佛
This-a-way. This-a-way. Look out.
往上拉
Up with it.
这边
Here.
你怎么连鞋都穿不好？
Why can't you hold still a minute?
天啊，夠了
My word. Enough of this!
请换下一位小姐 听到了吗，葛斯？
- The next young lady, please. - Did you hear that, Gus?
是啊 得快一点
- Yup. - uick, quick. Gotta hurry.
来啊，快点
ome on. Hurry.
醒醒，葛斯
Gus-Gus, come on.
你看，就在上面 快点
Look, look. Just up there. ome on.
我们来了，仙度瑞拉
Us a-coming, Cinderelly. Us a-coming.
我们能放你出去 你们拿到钥匙了!
- Us will get you out. - You've got the key!
你们怎么办到…
How did you ever manage to...?
鲁斯佛!
Lucifer!
放他走，鲁斯佛
Let him go, Lucifer.
求求你放了他
Please, let him go.
放了他 放了他!
- Let him go. - Let him go!
放了他 放了他，听见没？
Let him out! Let him out, you hear?
臭坏蛋
Lucify, you...
布鲁诺，对，布鲁诺!
Bruno. Yes, Bruno!
快点去找布鲁诺 找布鲁诺!
uick, get Bruno. Get Bruno!
没见过你这么笨的笨蛋
Of all the stupid little idiots.
我自己来
l'll do it myself.
滚开
Get away from me.
我一定给它穿上的
l'll make it fit.
好了 穿上了
- There. - lt fits.
穿上了？
lt fits?
不!
No!
大人，真的抱歉极了
Oh, Your Grace, l'm dreadfully sorry.
这不会再发生了 最好如此，夫人
- lt shan't happen again. - Precisely, madam.
快点，快点 葛斯，你快醒来
ome on, come on. Get up, Gus-Gus, get up.
别打了
Don't, don't, don't, don't, don't.
放手，放手
Let go, let go, let go.
我想这里就只有两位女孩
You are the only ladies in the household l hope... l presume.
没有其他人了，大人 好吧
- There's no one else, Your Grace. - uite so.
日安 大人？
- Good day. Good day. - Your Grace?
大人，请等一等
Your Grace, please, wait.
我可以试试吗？
May l try it on?
你别理她 她是仙度瑞拉
- Pay no attention to here. - lt's only Cinderella.
是家里的佣人 太荒谬了
- From the kitchen. - lt's ridiculous.
她疯了 她只是个爱幻想的孩子
- She's out of her mind. - Yes, ust an imaginative child.
夫人，皇令是说 每个女孩都要试
Madam, my orders were ''every maiden.''
来吧，孩子
ome, my child.
噢，不
Oh, no.
不，不…
No, no, no. Oh, no!
真是惨了
Oh, this is terrible.
国王会怎么说？
The king, what will he say?
他会杀了我 或许我能帮你
- What will he do? - Perhaps, if it would help...
不，谁都帮不了我 我死定了
No, no. Nothing can help now. Nothing.
可是，你看 我有另一只鞋
But, you see, l have the other slipper.
对自己的梦要有信心
Have faith in dreams
有一天
And someday
一切终将拨云见日
Your rainbow will come smiling through
无论你心里有多悲伤
No matter how your heart is grieving
只要你相信
If you keep on believing
你的梦想愿望
The dream that you wish
就会成真
Will come true
(从此他们 过着幸福快乐的日子)
(仙履奇缘)
谢谢观赏